<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Gradient IIITS</title>
    <link>http://gradient-iiits.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Gradient IIITS</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 20:56:37 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://gradient-iiits.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Square Root Decomposition</title>
      <link>http://gradient-iiits.github.io/posts/sqrt-decomposition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 20:56:37 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gradient-iiits.github.io/posts/sqrt-decomposition/</guid>
      <description>Square Root Decomposition Square Root Decomposition is an algorithm for answering range queries, in $\mathcal{O}(Q\sqrt{N})$, where $Q$ is the number of queries and $N$ is the number of elements in the range. It is very useful in a lot of CP questions. The basic technique of Square Root Decomposition can be used for doing certain queries on Trees as well.
Motivation Let us look at a problem, to motivate the need for this algorithm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Through Python3 (Day 2)</title>
      <link>http://gradient-iiits.github.io/posts/python3-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 00:18:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gradient-iiits.github.io/posts/python3-2/</guid>
      <description>Through Python3(Day 2) Hola Everyone, the Previous day we learned about how everything in Python is an object and about Mutable and Immutable Datatypes. If You haven’t the go through the link and read about them and come back again to join us.
Today we will be talking about Conditionals and Loops.
Conditionals So first let me tell you all about Conditionals. Python provides two ways to treat conditionals. The first one is the native way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Through Python3 (Day 1)</title>
      <link>http://gradient-iiits.github.io/posts/python3-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 00:18:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gradient-iiits.github.io/posts/python3-1/</guid>
      <description>Through Python3 (Day 1) Thanks for joining us! I am Krishna and I will be your host for this blog post. This blog post will be guiding you to learn basics of Python.
 A little girl goes into a pet show and asks for a wabbit. The shop keeper looks down at her, smiles and says: “Would you like a lovely fluffy little white rabbit, or a cutesy wootesly little brown rabbit?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Competitive Programming - How do I Start ?</title>
      <link>http://gradient-iiits.github.io/posts/competitive-programming-how-do-i-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 00:18:16 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gradient-iiits.github.io/posts/competitive-programming-how-do-i-start/</guid>
      <description>A lot of enthusiastic beginners are often intimidated by the huge amount of topics in CP and the amount of OJ’s on the web. As a result, due to lack of guidance they are let down ,take up inefficient learning methods and end up getting frustrated. This article aims to guide beginners on how to start your journey into the world of competitive programming.
These are the brief areas I wish to cover in this article:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Gradient</title>
      <link>http://gradient-iiits.github.io/posts/about-gradient/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2019 00:03:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gradient-iiits.github.io/posts/about-gradient/</guid>
      <description>Indian Institute of Information Technology, Sri City, Chittoor known as IIIT, Sri City is an institute of national importance, setting best-in-class technology education standards in India. IIITS was established in 2013 under the Government of India’s Initiative to set up 20 Institutes across India, focusing on Information Technology. The Institute was setup by the Government of India – MHRD, Government of Andhra Pradesh and Industry Partners represented by Sri City Foundation as a Not-for-Profit Public-Private-Partnership.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>